In the app, you may have noticed that all the headers have
在应用中 你也许注意到所有的标题看起来都是
the same visual style.
相同的样式
And you may have noticed that in the XML, that you had to
还有在 XML 中 你必须给这些标题
add the same attributes to each of these headers, the Toppings header,
添加相同的属性  如 Toppings 标题
the Quantity header as well as the Order Summary header when we used to have it.
Quantity 标题 以及 Order Summary 标题当我们使用的时候
If you have a lot of views with the same visual style,
如果你的很多 View 拥有相同的样式
it's good practice to try and reduce the repetition.
它是一个减少重复的很好的练习
By defining it in only one place and
在一个地方定义样式 然后
then referring back to that single place.
在需要的地方引用它
That way if the designer you work with wants to change how all of the headers
这样的话 如果和你一起工作的设计师想要在应用中改变所有标题样式
in her app look you can just change it in a single place and
你只需要在定义标题样式的地方修改即可
then it'll be updated everywhere.
所有引用标题的地方的样式也会随之更新
To do this we need to learn about defining styles in our app.
为了实现它 我们需要学习在的应用中定义样式
A style is a collection of properties that can be applied to a single view.
样式就是能够应用于单一 View 的属性的集合
Properties can include height, width, padding, font color,
属性包括高度 宽度 内边距 字体颜色
font size, and more.
字体大小 还有其他
Let's look at an example.
让我们来看一个例子
In a layout file this text used specifies a bunch of
在布局文件里 这个 TextView 定义了一组
different attributes.
不同的属性
But we can replace all these attributes with a single line that refers to
但是我们可以使用一行代码引用一个样式来代替
a style.
这些属性
One advantage to using a style is that you can separate the design of the view,
使用样式的一个优势就是你可以把 View 的设计和
how it looks, from the actual content of the view.
的内容分开
And in the end, both of these tech's views would look the same on a device.
最后 这两个视图在设备上看起来是一样的
Let's look at where the CodeFont style is defined.
我们看一下 CodeFont 样式是在哪里定义的
You can define the style within the styles.xml file,
你可以在 styles.xml 文件中定义样式
which is located in the res/values directory of your app.
这个文件在你的应用的 res/values 目录下
Now in this XML file, the root node has to be the resources XML element.
现在 在这个 XML 文件里 根节点必须是 resources 元素
Within that, you can specify as many style XML elements as you want.
在它的里面 你可以定义任何你想要的元素
For example, this is one style, and you could add more below this.
例如 这就是一个样式 在它的下面你可以添加更多的样式
For a given style XML element, you need to specify the name.
对于一个给定样式的 XML 元素 你必须指定样式的名字
In this case, it's CodeFont, but you could have picked a different name.
在这个例子里 它的名字是 CodeFont 但是你也可以使用其他的名字
Then you can add a list of all the different properties that should go in
然后你可以在这个样式里添加
this style.
一系列不同的属性
A property is defined using the item XML element.
属性通过 item 元素定义
For a given item, you have the name of the property, and
对于一个给定的 item 你必须指定属性的名称
then the value of the property is in between the open and the closing tags.
并且在开始标签和结束标签之间指定属性的值
If you want to create a style that builds off of existing styles,
如果你想以现有的样式为基础创建新的样式
you can specify the parent attribute here.
你可以在这指定父样式
But you don't have to specify a parent.
但这不是必要操作
This is optional.
是可选的
You can just define the style.
你可以只定义样式
And then add in the properties that you want.
然后添加你想要的属性
Then in your Layout File, you can simply refer to this style CodeFont.
然后在你的布局文件里 你只需要引用 CodeFont 样式就可以了
This is similar to how we refer to other resources in our app,
这和我们在应用里引用其他资源的方式很相似
like drawables, with the at drawable notation.
如 使用 @drawables 引用图片资源
Here's we're using @style/ the name of the resource.
这里我们通过使用 @style/ 加样式的名字引用样式
Also note that we specify the style using style equals and
注意我们使用 style = 而不是
not Android: style.
Android: style
Let's go back to our app for an example.
我们回到应用中看一个例子
Say we want to make all of the headings a dark purple text color,
我们想要让所有的标题都是深紫色
font size 20, and make it italicized.
字号是20  斜体
We could set the same attributes on each of these header text views or
我们可以给每个标题的 TextView 设置相同的属性
we could define it once in a single style, give it a name, and
我们也可以定义一个单独的样式 声明一个名字
then refer to that style every time we need it.
然后在我们需要的地方引用它
To define a style, go to the Resources, Values directory and
为了定义一个样式 打开 res/values 文件夹
find the Styles.XML file.
找到 styles.XML 文件
If it doesn't exist you could always create it by right clicking and
如果它不存在 你可以右击
going to new resource file, and then creating a style on XML file.
然后选择 new 再选择 Values resource file 创建一个
As we saw earlier, this XML file, like the strings done XML file,
就像我们先前看到的 这个 XML 文件同定义字符串的 XML文件一样
doesn't define a layout.
不是定义布局文件的
It's a resources file.
它是一个资源文件
In this case it defines a list of style resources,
这个例子里 它定义了样式资源列表
while the strings on XML file define a list of string resources.
而 strings.xml 文件是用来定义字符串资源
By the way, this is a comment.
顺便说一下 这是注释
So you can put anything you want in between this opening symbol,
所以你可以在开始标签和结束标签之间
and this closing symbol.
添加任意注释
And this is just supposed to describe the XML below it.
它是用来描述在它下面的 XML 文件的
I've just defined a style called CustomText.
我已经定义了一个叫做 CustomText 的样式
It contains three properties within it.
在它里面有三个属性
These are three attributes that can be applied to a TextView.
这是三个可以应用于 TextView 的属性
So we have the android text size property, android text color and
它们分别是 android:textSize  android:textColor
then android text style.
和 android:textStyle
The value for each of these attributes is shown here in between the item
在 item 的结束标签和开始标签之间
opening and closing tags.
定义了每个属性的值
We have the 20sp font size, the purple font color,
它们是 20sp 的字号 紫色的字体颜色
as well as the italic text style.
和斜体的字体样式
The possible attributes here depend on what view you are applying
这里的属性取决于你将样式应用
the style on to.
到什么 View 中
If you're going to use a custom text style on a text view, then all of
如果你想把 CustomText 样式应用到 TextView 中
the text view attributes that you're already familiar with can go here.
那么 你熟悉的 TextView 的属性都可以写在这里
If this style would be used on an image view,
如果样式将要应用到 ImageView 中
then the image view attributes would be valid here.
然后 ImageView 的属性可以定义在这里
Let's copy the name of this style and
我们复制这个样式的名字
then use it in the activity main layout file.
然后在 activity_main 布局文件里使用
For the toppings header, I'm going to apply a style onto the text view.
对于 Toppings 标题 我们在 TextView 中应用这个样式
I'm going to refer to the style using @style, slash, and
我们使用 @style/ 加
then the name of the style.
样式的名称引用样式
Then I can delete any attributes that
然后我就可以把样式里已经定义的
would have already been defined in the style.
属性删除
For this example I don't want the headers to be capitalized, so
对于这个示例 我不想要标题大写
I'm just going to erase this.
所以把这个属性删除
If I had a different text style or a different font color specified here,
如果我在这里定义了不同的文本样式或指定了不同的文本颜色
I would also delete that, now that I have this style here.
我也会删除 现在在这我有这个样式
Now I'm going to apply this style to the other header.
现在我将要把这个样式应用于其他标题
For the quantity header, I'm going to delete this.
对于 quantity 标题 我会删除这个
All caps, attribute, and just replace it with this style.
TextAllCaps 属性替换为这个样式
This is what the app looks like with the new style applied
这就是应用中所有标题 TextView 使用
to the header text views.
新样式后的样子
I could have put additional attributes inside the style,
我在这个样式中可以添加其他的属性
but it's really a trade-off and it's up to your own preference.
但是这是需要考虑的 它取决于你自己的喜好
Sometimes you want to leave the attributes inside the layout file, and
有时你想要在布局文件里定义属性
sometimes it's better if it's inside the style.
有时把它写在样式文件里会更好
All right, so the example I just gave you is not the style we actually want.
好了 刚才例子中的样式实际上并不是我们需要的样式
Instead, you'll need to use these attributes.
相反 你需要使用这些属性
We want our headers to have a height of 48dp with text vertically centered
我想要让标题的高度为 48dp 文本垂直居中
within that and with the text capitalized, as well.
并且大写
These values came from the material design spec,
这些值来自 Material Design 规范
you can see the instructor's notes for more details.
你可以在讲师注释中看到更多细节
We haven't covered the gravity attribute in depth but
我们还没有使用过 gravity 属性  但是
this just means we're centering the text vertically within the text field.
它的功能是在文本区域里设置文本垂直居中
So I want you to make a new style in the styles.xml file
所以我想让你在 styles.xml 文件里创建一个
called Header Text Style.
叫做 HeaderTextStyle 的新的样式
And it should contain these five properties.
它应该包含这5个属性
Next apply the style to all the header text views within the layout.
然后将这个样式应用到布局里的所有标题的 TextView 上
Make them all refer to this header text style.
让这些 TextView 都引用我们定义的样式
Be sure to remove any unnecessary XML in the layout file.
确保删除布局文件里不必要的属性
For example, you don't need to set the text sides of this header text view any
例如 你不需要再设置这个标题的 TextSize 属性
more because the text size is specified within the style now.
因为在样式中已经指定了这个属性
This is what the app should look like when you're done using a single style
这就是将这个样式应用到所有标题 TextView 后
for the headers.
应用的样子
Check these boxes when you're done.
做完这些后勾选这个框